怪獣 珍獣
Fearsome monsters... Exotic creatures...
財宝 秘宝
Vast riches... Hidden treasures...
魔境 秘境
Evil enclaves... Unexplored lands...
「未知」という言葉が放つ魔力
The word "unknown" holds magic.
その力に魅せられた すごい奴らがいる
And some incredible people are
drawn to that magic.
人は　彼らを…
They are known...
「ハンター」と呼ぶ
...as Hunters!
ゴンの奴 今日も　主釣りかい？
Gon's still trying to catch the Lord of the Lake?
えっ？　ええ…。
Huh? Y-Yes...
もう　かれこれ１週間 飽きもせず　ずっと。
He's been at it for a week, non-stop.
沼の主　釣り上げたら ハンター試験　受けていいって 約束したんだって？
You promised he could take the Hunter Exam
if he caught the Lord of the Lake?
バカ！　大の大人が ５人がかりでも上がらんのに
What a fool! Five adults couldn't manage to
reel in that monster.
子供１人の力で 上がるわけねえだろ！
How is a child supposed to catch that beast?
ミトさんは　ハンター試験 受けさせたくないんだよ。
Mito-san doesn't want him
taking the Hunter Exam.
でも ゴンの親父が釣り上げたのも ちょうど あの年くらいだったんだろ？
But Gon's old man was the same age
when he caught it...
ハハハ…　無理　無理
He can't do it.
来た！
Got him!
来た　来た　来た…！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes! I got him good!
デッケェな これが　沼の主か
It's huge! This is the Lord of the Lake?
２０年ぶりだとよ 知ってるよ
It's been twenty years!
あん時も　ゴンの父親だったろ
I know! It was Gon's father that time, right?
やっぱり　親子だね
He's his father's son.
ゴンの奴 ホントに　釣り上げやがった！
Gon actually caught the Lord!
なぁ　ミトさん。
Look, Mito-san!
ミトさん　俺　約束通り 主を釣り上げたよ！
Mito-san! I caught the Lord, as promised...
だから　ハンター試験 受けていいよね？
So I can take the Hunter Exam, right?
ねっ？
Right?
俺　頑張る 絶対　ハンターになってみせる！
I'll do my best. I promise to become a Hunter!
血は争えんねぇ
It must be in the blood...
ジンが１２の年に 釣り上げて以来
No one has been able to catch the Lord
誰も釣り上げられなかった 沼の主を
after Ging pulled it off, at the age of twelve.
息子のゴンが同じ年で 釣り上げるなんてねぇ。
And now his son has accomplished
the same feat, at the same age.
あの子の持つ目の光は 父親に　そっくりだ。
His eyes have the same shine as his father's.
もう　あの子を止める力は わしらには　ないよ。
We can no longer stop him.
本気なの？　ゴン。
Are you sure about this, Gon?
うん。
Uh-huh.
あんたのお父さんは まだ幼かった　あんたを捨てて
Your father abandoned you
when you were still young
ハンターの道を選んだ。
to become a Hunter.
知ってる。
I know.
あんたじゃなく ハンターを選んだのよ？
He chose becoming a Hunter over raising you!
すごいよね！ えっ？
Isn't that amazing? Huh?
子供を捨ててまで　続けたいって 思う仕事なんでしょ？
Being a Hunter is so great, he was willing
ハンターって。
to abandon his own kid!
ハンターは　危ない仕事なの！
It's a dangerous job!
いつ命を落とすか分からない 危険な職業なの！
You never know when you might lose your life!
分かってんの!?
Don't you understand?
分かんない。
I don't.
でも　知りたいんだ！
But I want to know more!
親父が夢中になった ハンターって仕事を
I want to become a Hunter and discover why
俺も　やってみたいんだ！
it was so important to my dad!
やっぱり　ジンの子ね。
You really are Ging's son...
俺　合格するから。
I promise I'll pass the exam.
必ず合格して ハンターになるから！
I'll pass the exam, and I'll become a Hunter!
必ず　無事に帰って来ること。
Just promise that you'll come back safe.
約束できる？
Can you do that?
うん！　約束する！
Uh-huh, I promise!
ウソついたら 針千本　のます
Pinky swear made... Whoever breaks their promise has
to swallow a thousand needles.
誓いのチュ！ 誓いのチュ！ チュ！
Sealed with a kiss!
ゴン…。
Gon...
ありがとう　ミトさん。
Thank you, Mito-san.
頑張れよ！
Good luck!
行っといで！
Knock 'em dead!
絶対に 世界一のハンターになるから！
I'm going to become the
best Hunter in the world!
世界一のハンターになって 必ず　戻って来るから！
Once I'm the best Hunter
in the world, I'll come back!
フフフ… 「世界一のハンター」ねぇ
The best Hunter in the world?
えっ。 ナメられたもんだなぁ。 ハンター試験には
Kid doesn't respect us.
毎年　全世界から数百万人の 腕利きが集まるんだ
Every year, there are millions of skilled
applicants for the Hunter Exam.
だが　選ばれるのは ほんの　ひと握り
But only a handful are selected.
めったなことを 口にするもんじゃねえぜ　坊ず。
Don't say stuff that you can't back up, boy.
そんなんじゃ 立派な船乗りには　なれねえぜ。
At this rate, you'll never make a decent sailor.
ハハハ…！ 何だ？　その　へっぴり腰は。
Why are you bent over?
おい　てめぇら！
Hey, losers!
サボってんじゃねえぞ！
Don't slack off!
へ…　へい！
A-Aye, sir!
おい！
Hey...
聞こえなかったのか？ さっさと運べ！
Didn't you hear me? Move that box!
は…　はい！　船長。 待って！
A-Aye, Captain! Hold on.
あぁ　あっ…　ありがとう。
Thanks!
嵐が来るよ。
A storm's coming.
ん？　どうして分かる？　小僧。
How can you tell, boy?
だって ウミヅルが　そういってる。
That's what the seagulls are saying.
何？ それに…。
What? Plus...
ものすごく　デッカい嵐が来るよ！
It's a huge storm that's coming!
おぉ!? 本当だって！
It's true...
においで分かるんだ！
I can tell by the smell!
あの坊ず…
That boy...
あの目は　ひょっとして…
Those eyes... Could he be...
船長！
Captain!
このままじゃ マストが持ちません！
The mast won't last much longer!
帆を下ろしましょう！ バカいえ！
We should lower the sails! Don't be stupid!
これからが おもしれぇとこじゃねえか！ フン！
The fun's about to start.
行くぜぇ！
Here we go!
取りかじ　いっぱい！
Full to port!
飛ぶぞ！
Let's fly!
あ！　まぁまぁの波だったな。
Those waves weren't much...
おい　かじを代われ。 へっ　へい！
Hey, take the helm. A-Aye!
まったく うちの船員達も　だらしねえ。
Damn, this is one lousy crew.
全滅だ　こりゃ　情けねえ。
Not a one of them can stand. Pathetic.
こんなんで　ハンター試験 受けようってんだから
And they're supposed to be
taking the Hunter Examination.
ハッ　まったく　笑わせやがる。
What a laugh!
はい　これ　薬草 ん？
Here are some herbs.
噛めば　少しは楽になるよ。
If you chew them, you'll feel a little better.
み…　水…。
W-Water...
すぐに持って来るから　待ってて。
It's coming, so hold on.
あの坊ず…。
That boy...
酸っぺぇリンゴだな。
This is one sour apple...
なるほど　ちっとは骨のありそうな 奴らが　いるようだな。
I see. There are a few tough nuts on board.
すんません！ おぉ!?
Excuse me!
は…　はい　水！ ありがとう。
H-Here is your water! Thanks.
さぁ　飲んで。
Now drink your fill.
ありがとう 助かったよ　カッツオさん。
Thanks. I really appreciate it, Katsuo-san.
まず　３人の名前を聞こうか。
First, tell me your names.
俺　ゴン！ 私はクラピカ。
I'm Gon! I'm Kurapika.
レオリオだけど。
It's Leorio.
お前ら　なぜ ハンターになりたいんだ？
Why do you want to become Hunters?
おい！　試験官でもねえのに 偉そうに聞くんじゃ　ねえ！
Hey! If you're not an examiner,
you can't boss us around!
いいから答えろ。
Just answer the question!
俺は　親父がハンターなんだ。
My dad is a Hunter.
親父が魅せられたハンターって仕事が どんなものなのか
I left Whale Island because I want to know
どうしても知りたくて くじら島から出て来た。
why my dad desired so much to be a Hunter.
くじら島… やはり　こいつがジンの息子
Whale Island... So this is Ging's son.
とうとう　この日が来よったか
The day has finally come.
おい　ガキ！ えっ？
Hey, kid! Huh?
横から勝手に答えてんじゃ　ねえ！ いいじゃん　理由を話すくらい。
You're not supposed to answer his question! Why can't I tell him why I'm here?
協調性のねえ奴だな 俺は嫌なんだよ。
Not a team player, huh? I don't wish to reveal why I'm here.
私も　レオリオに同感だな。
I agree with Leorio.
なっ　おい！　てめぇも年下だろ！
What? Hey! Aren't you younger than I am?
俺を呼び捨てにしてんじゃ　ねえ！
Show some respect!
もっともらしいウソをついて
It's quite simple to avoid pesky questions
嫌な質問を 回避するのは　たやすい。
by offering a plausible lie.
おい！　聞いてんのか!?
Hey! Are you listening to me?
しかし 偽証は最も恥ずべき行為だ。
However, it is quite shameful to rely upon deceit.
かといって　正直に告白するには 私の志望動機は　あまりにも 私の心に深くかかわり過ぎている。
That said, if I were to tell you the truth, I would be exposing my deepest secrets.
従って ここで答えることはできない。
That is why I cannot provide an answer.
てめぇ　無視すんじゃ　ねえ！
Hey, you... Don't ignore me!
つまり　俺の質問には 答えられないと。
In other words,
you refuse to answer my question.
おい　カッツオ。 はい　船長。
Hey, Katsuo. Aye, Captain.
この２人も脱落者として 審査委員会に報告だ。
Tell the examination board that
we have two more dropouts.
はっ。 どういうこと？
What do you mean?
まだ分かんねえのか。
You still haven't figured it out?
ハンター試験は とっくに始まってんだよ。
The Hunter Examination has already begun.
何!? 何!?
What?
ハンターの資格を とりたい奴らは
There are as many Hunter wannabes
世界に星の数ほどいる。
as there are stars in the sky.
そいつら全部を審査できるほど 試験官に人的余裕も　時間も　ねえ。
The examiners don't have the time or
resources to review them all.
そこで　俺達みてぇのが雇われて 受験者をふるいに　かけてるのさ。
So they hire people like us, to trim the fat.
すでに　お前ら３人以外は
I've already notified the board
脱落者として 審査委員会に報告した。
that everyone else on this ship had to withdraw.
あの程度で くたばってるようじゃ この先のハンター試験なんて 到底　無理だからな。
If they couldn't handle a little storm, they'd stand no chance in the
Hunter Examination's later stages.
つまり　お前らが 本試験を受けられるかどうかは 俺の気分次第ってことだ。
In other words, you only proceed to
the main exam if I pass you.
よく考えて 俺の質問に答えるこったな。
So think carefully before you answer my question.
だってさ。
So he says...
それを早く　いえってんだ。
Should have told us sooner.
私は　クルタ族の生き残りだ。
I am the last survivor of the Kurta Clan.
４年前　私の同胞を皆殺しにした 盗賊グループ
Four years ago, my clan was annihilated
by a band of criminals.
「幻影旅団」を捕まえるため ハンターを志望している。
I wish to become a Hunter and
hunt down that band, the Phantom Troupe.
賞金首ハンター志望か。
So you want to become a bounty hunter?
「幻影旅団」はＡ級首だぜ。
The Phantom Troupe is a Class-A bounty.
熟練のハンターでも うかつに手を出せねえ。
Not even the most grizzled Hunters
can touch them.
無駄死にすることになるぜ。
You'd be throwing away your life.
死は　全く怖くない。
I do not fear death.
一番恐れるのは　この怒りが
I fear only that my rage
やがて　風化してしまわないか ということだ。
will fade over time.
要は　敵討ちだろ？
So, in other words, you want revenge.
だったら　わざわざ ハンターにならなくたって できるじゃねえか。
Does that require that you become a Hunter?
この世で 最も愚かな質問の１つだな　レオリオ。
That may be the stupidest question
I've ever heard, Leorio.
「レオリオさん」だ！
That's Leorio-san to you!
ハンターでなければ入れない場所 聞けない情報
Places accessible only to Hunters... Information otherwise unobtainable...
できない行動というものが
Actions otherwise impossible...
君の脳みそに 入り切らないくらいあるんだよ。
There are more reasons than your
brain could possibly handle.
フギギ…！ ねぇ！
Hey!
レオリオさんは 何でハンターになりたいの？
Why do you want to become a Hunter, Leorio-san?
俺か？　俺の目的は　ずばり…
Me? I'll make it short.
金さ。 ん？
I want money.
金さえありゃ 何でも手に入るからな！
Money can get you everything!
デカい家！　いい車！
A big house! A nice car!
うまい酒！　かぁ！
Good liquor!
品性は金で買えないんだよ レオリオ。
You can't buy class with money, Leorio.
３度目だぜ。
That's three times now.
表へ出な。
Step outside.
その薄汚いクルタ族の血ってやつを 絶やしてやるぜ。
I'll end the filthy Kurta bloodline, here and now.
取り消せ　レオリオ！
Take that back, Leorio!
取り消せ。
Take that back!
「レオリオさん」だ。
That's Leorio-san to you.
チッ。
Hey, boys!
おい　お前ら！ 俺の話は　まだ終わってねえぞ！
I'm not finished yet!
放っておこうよ。 ん？
Just let them go. Huh?
昔　ミトさんが教えてくれたんだ。
Mito-san once told me...
((その人を知りたかったら その人が何に怒っているのか
If you want to get to know someone, you need to make an effort
知る努力をしなさい))
to learn why they're angry.
今　２人が怒ってる理由は とても大切なんだよ。
It's important for them to
understand why they're mad.
だから放っておいたほうが いいと思うんだ。
So we should let them settle it themselves.
船長！ ん？
Captain!
あ…　あれを。 なっ…！
L-Look...
あんな竜巻に巻き込まれたら 船は　ひとたまりもない！
If we get caught by that waterspout,
the ship will sink.
急いで帆を下ろせ！ はい！
Lower the sails now.
俺も手伝うよ！ うん！　ついて来て。
Aye! I'll help! Uh-huh, come with me.
ここは俺に任せろ。 へい！
I'll take the helm. Aye!
面かじ　いっぱい！
Full to starboard!
急げ！
Hurry!
竜巻に 巻き込まれちまうぞ！
The waterspout is gonna catch us!
さっきの言葉　訂正しろ！
Take back what you said!
訂正すれば許してやるぞ レオリオ。
Take back your words,
and I'll forgive you, Leorio.
何度も　いわせるなよ てめぇのほうが先だ。
How many times must I repeat myself? You should show me some respect.
俺から譲る気は　全く　ねえ。
I won't back down.
仕方ない。
Then I have no choice...
あっ！　カッツオさん！ あっ！
Katsuo-san!
クソ！　あっ！ くっ！　あっ！
Damn it!
このボケ！
You idiot!
俺達が おめぇの足をつかめなかったら おめぇは今頃 海の藻くずだったんだぞ！
If we hadn't grabbed your legs, you'd be shark bait now.
まったく　無謀極まりない。
Honestly... How reckless can you be?
でも　つかんでくれたじゃん。
But you did catch me.
えっ？ あ…。
Huh?
２人して　つかんでくれたじゃん！
You both caught me!
それは　そうだが…。
Well, I guess so...
ゴン！
Gon!
カッツオさん！
Katsuo-san!
ありがとう　ゴン！　命の恩人だ！
Thanks, Gon! You saved my life.
俺が助けたわけじゃ　ないよ。
I couldn't have done it alone.
この２人がいたから助かったんだ。
These two helped save you.
えっ。 えっ。
Huh?
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much!
いや　礼には及ばぬ。
No, you don't need to thank me.
まぁ　あれだ… 助かってよかったな。
Well... Yeah, I'm glad you're okay.
はい！　それじゃあ　俺 持ち場に戻ります！
Yeah! So I'll be returning to my station!
何だよ。
What?
今までの非礼を詫びよう。
I apologize for my rude behavior.
すまなかった　レオリオさん。
Sorry, Leorio-san.
な…　何だよ　いきなり。
Wh-What's with the sudden change?
水くせぇ レオリオでいいよ　レオリオで。
We sound like strangers... Just call me Leorio... Leorio works.
俺も悪かったな。 あ…。
I'm also sorry.
さっきの言葉は　全面撤回する。
I take back everything I said.
すまなかった。 いや　いいんだ。
I was wrong. No, it's okay.
お前ら　気に入ったぜ。
I like you guys!
よし　お前ら３人は 俺様が責任を持って
Okay! I'll take responsibility for bringing
審査会場　最寄りの港まで 連れて行ってやらぁ　ハハ！
you three to the port closest to the exam site.
ホント？
Really?
じゃあ　試験は？
What about your test?
いったろ　俺様の気分次第だって。
Like I said... It's my decision to make.
３人とも合格だ。
And all three of you pass!
い…！　やった！ ハハハ…。
Yay!
こうして　ゴンの旅が始まった
And so began Gon's journey...
父親の後を追い ハンターになるために
To follow in his father's footsteps
and become a Hunter.